CLAUDIA CORREA SALHAB

2727 Henry Hudson Parkway #608 Bronx, NY 10463

Cell: 646.591.6033

E-Mail: claudiacorreasalhab@gmail.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS:	
	 22 years of Web Development & Software Design experience 7 years of OTT (Mobile/CD/SmartTVs) Engineering 5 years of Integration Engineering & Professional Services Excellent client and customer service skills Dedicated to learning & keeping current with new technologies
WORK EXPERIENCE:	
Conviva New York, NY 01.2016 - 02.2021	Sr. Integration Engineer Assisted tier-1 customers CNN, AT&T, MLB, NBA, March Madness, ESPN, NBC Sports, TNT/TBS/TruTV, Cartoon Network, TCM, HBO, Discovery, Bloomberg, WWE and 20 add'l tier-2 customers (Sky Brasil, Canada's Bell Media, CBS, Cinepolis, Warner Bros Digital Lab - DC Comics, IBM Interactive, Australia's Optus) integrate various Conviva analytics SDKs into their video platforms for QoE metrics Video player expertise: Web HTML5 (VideoElement/Video.JS/Brightcove), Android Exoplayer, iOS AVFoundation, Roku Scenegraph & Microsoft's UWP SME for customer's developers/engineers/VPs building trusted relationships, so much so that those SWEs would engage on non-analytics coding questions Helped integrate 500+ players & bug fixing along the iterations Support Javascript, Java, Objective-C, Swift, Brightscript & C CMAF/HLS/DASH master manifest & renditions/bitrates Provided tips on error codes, handling and reporting Assisted vendors (Globant, Accedo, WalterThompson/Possible) Agile lifecycle: JIRA tickets creation, sizing, planning Helped with Google IMA & Freewheel ads hook into analytics Leveraged proprietary tool Touchstone & Charles to debug Set up Charles to proxy & inspect network traffic Helped design proprietary reporting tool which Quality Engineering department used to generate validation info Designed reporting templates for issues Tech poc for field team (Solutions Consultants & Sales Dir's) Onboarded other IEs, QEs & PMs Captured technical docs on customers varying workflows Assisted Support Engineers with troubleshooting Fielded questions on APIs Reviewed tech docs from Editorial & Sensor Engineer teams Participated in design reviews on sensors development Reversed engineered sensors Detected bugs in Conviva's SDKs as well as Pulse platform products (Experience/QoE, Ad, Content & Player Insights) Opened ~ 300 JIRA tickets (bugs and improvements) COPA / CCPA / GDPR compliant Traveled for customer onsite visits (in 2019, I traveled 20x)

The Walt Disney Company ESPN

Bristol, CT 12.2012 - 10.2015

Sr. Software Engineer

• Watch Product (Video) – <u>Domestic & International</u>

Support linear channels: (E1/E2/EU/ENews/Deportes/GoalLine/BuzzBeater/

SEC/Longhorn) & online/events-based channels: (E3/SEC+)

Upgraded to add support for HLS & HDS (was only RTMP prior)

Upgraded to add new linear networks SEC & SEC+

Engineered Stream Limiting for SlingTV inclusion

Bug fixed AdobePass integration

Bug fixed Closed Caption integration

Upgraded player's configuration & enhanced CMS for config

Consolidated multiple players into 1 code base to support Watch /

Syndicated & Chromeless (MVPD's version) players

Provided assistance to Comcast, AT&T & Charter on Chromeless integrations

- Built OTT Watch (Cricket World Cup leveraging CSG Entitlement System's API)
- Vendor Management (SOW / Sprint & Poker Planning)
- Upgraded ESPN's API for video clip inclusion & endcard/related treatments
- Added new Java Applications to custom ESPN Admin
- Engineer on Video Platform (Java Spring f/w) / Integrated with FreeWheel, Brightcove & Ooyala besides GoPub CMS / built RESTful endpoints
- Liaison to TechnologyOps (24-hour monitoring team)
- Provide support to TechOps / AdOps / ContentOps / AffiliateOps / Programming / Production teams
- Tech Lead on Brightcove POC video.js player
- Built lightweight browser based tools for video catalog & administration
- Enhanced Flash/Flex based tools for video monitoring
- Enhanced Cue Point markers / ID3 parsing
- Enhanced Milestones/Highlight clips to be HDS for FIFA security regulations
- Provided support to Radio team on Audio products
- Assisted in new AuthZ layer for video
- Documented troubleshooting steps for many, various issues
- Debugged many TEA templates & services and many Java applications
- Discovered recursion in Int'l's domain model
- Scrum Master / Agile Methodology
- Learned Android Development

The Walt Disney Company Disney Interactive Media Group North Hollywood, CA 04.2008 – 11.2012

Lead & Sr. Software Engineer

- Tech Lead on 5 (full stack) LAMP projects securing back channel calls (MakeYourMark Style-Studio; Phineas & Ferb Music Video Player; Disney Channel Halloween & MonstOber stunts; WordPress Collections)
- Tech Lead on 3 Java (CMS / TomCat / TEA templates) projects
 (Disney DVD Portal; Disney Digital Books; Disney Junior w/ActiveMQ)
- Agile Methodology to Software Development & Project Management
- Kanban Rapid Board Ticket Queuing System
- Setup & managed Apache web-server & vhosts for Local Development
- Hooked into Continuous Integration (TeamCity) system
- Engineered Send To A Friend & Shout Out modules for Disney Channel
- Integrated STAF with Proprietary Email Campaign System (Beacon)
- Removed legacy Family Contest Framework & integrated to Take180's
 MYDCast Platform (includes photo & video upload and voting mechanisms)
- Worked w/ Systems & QA Engineering to configure Preview environment for Disney Junior's It's Your Birthday
- Developed XML based Audio Player
- Developed a voting module that generated 1.7 million submissions
- Upgraded a rating & voting module on Radio's Next Big Thing (NBT) to call our Global Registration System, adding a newer process flow
- Tied Polls functionality into our Quiz.Java Engine
- Generated Game IDs on Scores Engine & connected many games to it
- Sr. Flash/ActionScript 3.0 Engineer on hundreds of features & sites
- Extensive usage of FlashVars & External API communication to HTML / JS
- Exhaustive Error Handling with Test Driven Development
- Collaborated on Engineering Video Players
- Troubleshoot Proprietary TEA language / Programmed in custom frameworks
- Generated XML & JSON results from TEA templates
- Utilized Proprietary Admin Tool Client to manage several CMS's
- · Created content objects in GoPublish CMS's
- Scripted several .sql files to retrieve relevant & update data from SQL Server
- Coded Analytics Page & Link Tracking hooking into Omniture Suite
- Incorporated DoubleClick Ad code
- Enforced Code Externalization & Localization
- Applied Proxy Servers
- Vendor Management
- Conducted and Reported on Code Reviews & Performance Testing
- Generated Documentation & Organized Information
- IPs / Business Units supported:

Disney XD, WD Records, Disney Interactive Studios;

Buena Vista Home Entertainment; Disney Consumer Products;

Walt Disney Studios Movies Production;

Disney Publishing Worldwide;

Live Events; Disney Books;

Parks & Resorts;

Corporate; DIMG Communications

Correa Web Development &	Web & ActionScript Developer / Web & Catalog Designer
Consulting, Inc. Plantsville, CT 01.1999 – Present	 XML & AS 2.0 coding for Clearpoint Learning 12.05 – 02.06 http://www.clearpointlearning.com/ Built, customized and integrated modular e-courses and training systems for their Pharmaceutical Client, Johnson & Johnson Provided technical support to designers and team during out-source transition Incorporated video delivery (via core NetStream class) Designed (layout composition in Photoshop) and coded Flash websites for: Williams Sonoma (Business Sales Designer & Home Furnishings) 08.05 Louie Music (Children's Development Music) 09.05 Shescape (Women's Entertainment Promoter) 03.05 – 12.07 PlumsInNewYork (Off-Broadway Theater Show) 08.04 Suenos Discos (Latin Music DJ) 03.03 Smooch-a-roo (Independent Cosmetics) 04.02 FAO Schwarz Art Director's liaison to & manager at pre-press printing shop, coordinating a team of 15 working color correction & 4-color separation on the '99 & Holiday Catalogs Portugal Ceramics – Developed e-commerce site (HTML forms & JavaScript
	& Cookies); Produced in Director a hybrid CD-ROM of product line
Crackle, Inc. – a Sony Pictures Entertainment Company Sausalito, CA 03.2007 – 02.2008	 Sr. Flash Developer Coded in AS3 & AS2 & Proprietary Object-Oriented API video players Assisted development of Member's Browsing Panels tool in Flex Builder Maintained Flex-built custom Upload tool Developed AS2 Video Players integrated with DoubleClick & 24/7 Ad Serving Systems (one of the players was for embedding & sharing on Facebook) & Flash 8 Video Player to support legacy guest plugins Implemented Cairngorm microarchitecture & MVC design pattern Extensive usage of Flash's XPathAPI to search through static XML Configured local IIS web servers & SQL Server 2005 database aliases

Coded in HTML / CSS Content Creators section

Integrated HitBox, IPro & internal tracking calls

Bug Tracking via Microsoft Visual Studio's Team Explorer, fixing issues

RMG Connect (JWT's Digital Media/Relationship Marketing) New York, NY 02.2006 – 02.2007	 Sr. Software Engineer / Technology Lead Managed technology team of 5 FTE's & 5 Freelancers Maintained Oracle 8i database (for Diamond Trading Company client); Wrote SQL scripts to pull weekly reports. Deployed DTC's 2006 initiative microsites: journey.adiamondisforever.com diamondrighthandring.adiamondisforever.com christmas.adiamondisforever.com (launched 11.17.06 – 01.15.07) Maintained DTC's adiamondisforever.com consumer website & App Server Deployed DTC's P.R. website: diamondfacts.org along with localization of 16 languages, translations of the site (heavy usage of CSS & includes) Worked w/ Akamai to deliver / stream journey.adiamondisforever.com Developed Proprietary (PHP) CMS and its Admin Tool GUI for DTC's df.org Maintained (client) T Rowe Price's 4 microsites: mutualfunds.troweprice.com, ira.troweprice.com, rollover.troweprice.com, myira.troweprice.com Assisted Analysts with parsing web server (Apache & IIS) logs Coded several newsletters for email campaigns for T Rowe Price & HSBC Assisted Flash Designers integrate metrics code & back-end/db hooks Implemented WebTrends SDC technology on all new initiatives for all clients
Revion New York, NY 06.2003 – 05.2005	 Sr. Flash Developer / Client-Side Web Developer Engineer of revlon.com (Homepage, What's New, Halle Retrospect, Awards, Reg, Around The World) & almay.com (Category pg's interactive scrollbars) Project Leader, UX / UI Designer, Programmer on Age Defying's brand "Product Migration" tool, where I also integrated to an SQL database Developed stunts & coordinated launches for various campaigns* (*multiple summer & holiday shade promos; Kiss For The Cause - Fight Against Breast; On The Red Carpet) Met client's demand for robust functionality, intuitive navigation and low file size for various bandwidths consideration Designed & Coded several newsletters for email campaigns Developed Proprietary CMS (.Net data-grid based) and its Admin Tool GUI, Integrated CMS with SQL Server 2000 Updated Face Tool created by 3rd Party Ad Agency (iDeutsch)
Hearst Interactive Studio New York, NY 05.2000 – 02.2002	 Web Developer / Project & Tech Lead Managed 4 developers & 3 interns Created (PHP/HTML forms) CMS w/ (Perl) Workflow PopularMechanics.com Integrated TeamSite CMS to esquire.com Developed Esquire's "ThingsAManShouldKnow" sitelet & EmailToAFriend tool (captured user's IP and stored in MySQL for added security measures) Designed & Developed KingFeatures.com & its Admin Tool GUI

ENGINEERING SKILLS:	
Programming Languages	 HTML / HTML5 / CSS / JavaScript / JSON / XML / Perl / PHP MERN Stack (MongoDB/Mongoose - ExpressJS - REACT - Node.js) Object Oriented Programming: Java & ActionScript SQL & UML (Unified Modeling Language) Swift / Objective-C / Brightscript / C Apollo with GraphQL jQuery / Boostrap / Moment.js 3rd Party APIs (Open Weather Map, NY Times, Google Books, etc) CRUD Operations
Authoring/IDE's, Tools , Documentation (Wiki) & Compilation	 Jira / Trello / Confluence / Sharepoint / Postman / cURL XCode (Cocoa Pods) & Android Studio (Gradle) Eclipse & Spring Tool Suite (STS) (other Dependency Manager: Maven) Flex Builder 3.0 / Flash Builder 4.7 / CS5 Suite (Flash/PhotoShop/Illustrator) Sublime / TextWrangler / HomeSite / BBEdit / Notepad++ / Notepad2 BeyondCompare (Difference & Merge & Touch tool) Visual Paradigm & Visio (UML) FTP / sFTP: FileZilla / WinSCP Microsoft Visual Studio 2008 & 2005 vi (Linux Shell & Command Line Editor) SmartBear Code Collaborator (code review tool)
Databases	 MongoDB (NOSQL) MySQL / MS SQL Server (Enterprise Manager & Express Edition) / MS Access phpMyAdmin Database Administration & Oracle 8i Local Storage / IndexedDB
Application Servers	 RedHat Linux Apache with PHP or Perl Spring & DropWizard (Java) Frameworks MicroSoft IIS (& usage of IISAdmin.NET & tool for multiple site definition) TomCat / Proprietary Barista (TomCat flavor) built at TWDC TeamCity & Jenkins Continuous Integration Varnish (cache / CygWin / Purge Command Line Interface) Proprietary Stout (cache / Purge tool in Perl) CDN (Akamai / LimeLight / Level3 / Purge tools) NPM, RPM & YUM (Software Package Managers) Heroku Deployment / MongoDB Atlas
Network Administration	 Unix Shell (putty) / Telnet / SSH / Mac Terminal Charles Proxy & Fiddler HTTP Packet Network Request tools Chrome's Developer Tools Cisco AnyConnect (VPN) / RSA SecurID Token / Key Fob / Duo
Content Management Systems	 Interwoven TeamSite WordPress Proprietary GoPublish (Java) w/ Content Editor admin client Proprietary .NET CMS built for Revlon/Almay/CosmeticsAndMore Proprietary CMS (Perl) with a WorkFlow (PHP) built for Popular Mechanics
Version Control & Bug Tracking	 Git & GitHub / Perforce / CVS & JIRA / Trello MicroSoft Visual Studio 2008/2005 & SourceSafe & Team Explorer
Office/Productivity	 Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, Access & PowerPoint) Android Smart Phone Email & Calendar client apps

EDUCATION:	
	PACE UNIVERSITY – Pleasantville, NY
	Bachelor of Science – Dual Majors: Computer Science & Mathematics
	COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY - SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING
	CERTIFICATE - FULL STACK DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP 2021 FT SUMMER COURSE